<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Development on DouglasDev</title>
    <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/tags/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Development on DouglasDev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/tags/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Use AI in Programming Without Losing Your Mind (or Your Code)</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/how-to-use-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/how-to-use-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing software development. It&amp;rsquo;s up to us to decide if that revolution of for the better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI helps debug errors, explain messy code, generate unit tests, and even teach complex concepts. But if you’re not careful, it can also turn into a crutch—or worse, a trap.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen junior developers blindly copy-paste AI-generated code into their (and even my) projects, only to spend hours later trying to fix the mess. So, how do you actually use AI the right way? Let’s break it down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Learning Java still Worth It in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/java-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/java-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I had a dollar for every time I heard &amp;ldquo;Java is dead,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d probably be writing this from a beach somewhere. (I&amp;rsquo;m not, unfortunetly)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet, here we are in 2025, and &lt;strong&gt;Java is still one of the most widely used programming languages in the world&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, when I started diving deeper into software development, I wondered if learning Java was worth it. With so many modern languages getting all the hype, sticking with Java felt like going against the tide. But the more I explored the industry, the more I realized Java wasn’t just alive—it was thriving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
