<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DouglasDev</title>
    <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DouglasDev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons I Learned About Leadership (That No One Told Me)</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/3-leadership-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/3-leadership-lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I transitioned from being a developer to a tech lead, I knew things would change. What I didn’t realize was how much I had to learn—fast. Leadership isn’t just about being good at your craft; it’s about navigating a whole new set of responsibilities, many of which no one prepares you for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In just one week, I ran into multiple leadership challenges that completely shifted my perspective. Here are some of the most important lessons I learned—lessons I wish someone had told me earlier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Use AI in Programming Without Losing Your Mind (or Your Code)</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/how-to-use-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/how-to-use-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing software development. It&amp;rsquo;s up to us to decide if that revolution of for the better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI helps debug errors, explain messy code, generate unit tests, and even teach complex concepts. But if you’re not careful, it can also turn into a crutch—or worse, a trap.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen junior developers blindly copy-paste AI-generated code into their (and even my) projects, only to spend hours later trying to fix the mess. So, how do you actually use AI the right way? Let’s break it down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Every Back-end Developer Must Master their ORM</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/master-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/master-orm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No experience is ever completely exclusive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though I believe I belong to a minority of back-end developers who work more directly with the database than with the ORM, I’ll still share my experience so that it doesn’t happen to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-an-orm&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s an ORM?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those who might be new to the term, &lt;strong&gt;ORM (Object-Relational Mapping)&lt;/strong&gt; is a technique or technology that allows developers to map application objects to relational database tables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How this Japanese Philosophy Changed My Life</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/lifechanging-kaizen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/lifechanging-kaizen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I used to believe that growth came from big, dramatic changes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A major career move, learning an entirely new programming language overnight, or making a complete overhaul of my daily routine. I thought that if I wasn’t making big moves, I wasn’t moving forward at all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, I stumbled upon &lt;strong&gt;Kaizen&lt;/strong&gt;—a Japanese philosophy that completely changed the way I approach my work, my career, and my personal development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2025 Learning Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/study-roadmap-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/study-roadmap-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of each year, I like to set clear learning goals to push myself further as a software engineer. But if there’s one thing I’ve learned, it’s that a &lt;strong&gt;vague goal without a structured plan is just wishful thinking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s why, instead of saying “&lt;em&gt;I want to get better at Java”&lt;/em&gt; or “&lt;em&gt;I should learn cloud computing&lt;/em&gt;,” I&amp;rsquo;ve broken my learning into focused, quarterly goals that align with my daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Learning Java still Worth It in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/java-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/java-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I had a dollar for every time I heard &amp;ldquo;Java is dead,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d probably be writing this from a beach somewhere. (I&amp;rsquo;m not, unfortunetly)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet, here we are in 2025, and &lt;strong&gt;Java is still one of the most widely used programming languages in the world&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, when I started diving deeper into software development, I wondered if learning Java was worth it. With so many modern languages getting all the hype, sticking with Java felt like going against the tide. But the more I explored the industry, the more I realized Java wasn’t just alive—it was thriving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a Blog?</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/why-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/why-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a writer—well, except for that one time in freshman year when my teacher gave me a 3 out of 10 in an essay. Yeah, dark times.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But aside from that, I used to write poems as a teenager (never shared them, though), fiction as a kid, and I loved crafting DnD campaigns in my early 20s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technical writing found me around 2022, when I was trying to break into Data Science and everyone kept saying, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You need a Medium blog to share what you learn.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial - Spring Boot &amp; AWS S3 for Image Storing</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/spring-aws-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/spring-aws-s3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; my wife was busy on a Sunday afternoon. Do you know what that means? Yeah&amp;hellip; It means I&amp;rsquo;m going to code my a*s off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to start playing with AWS for sometime now, and this week I thought of an interesting use for AWS S3 at work and wanted to test it out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea is to store and retrieve images on S3 using a Spring Boot Application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/my-fist-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/my-fist-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, beginnings are always a bit akward, aren&amp;rsquo;t they?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is mainly supposed to just exist, just be the first milestone of this blog and to make sure it exists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really hope this turns out well. I hope everyone can benefit from this ackward endeavor of mine to build a blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stay around with me and see where this goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:30:34 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contact me through any of the socials bellow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/douglas-rocha-leite&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DouglasRFLeite&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@douglas.rochedo&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:29:43 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here you will find my most important projects&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:22:09 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here you will be able to learn a bit more about myself and my carrer as a &lt;strong&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
