<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on DouglasDev</title>
    <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on DouglasDev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Every Back-end Developer Must Master their ORM</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/master-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/master-orm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No experience is ever completely exclusive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though I believe I belong to a minority of back-end developers who work more directly with the database than with the ORM, I’ll still share my experience so that it doesn’t happen to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-an-orm&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s an ORM?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those who might be new to the term, &lt;strong&gt;ORM (Object-Relational Mapping)&lt;/strong&gt; is a technique or technology that allows developers to map application objects to relational database tables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2025 Learning Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/study-roadmap-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/study-roadmap-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of each year, I like to set clear learning goals to push myself further as a software engineer. But if there’s one thing I’ve learned, it’s that a &lt;strong&gt;vague goal without a structured plan is just wishful thinking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s why, instead of saying “&lt;em&gt;I want to get better at Java”&lt;/em&gt; or “&lt;em&gt;I should learn cloud computing&lt;/em&gt;,” I&amp;rsquo;ve broken my learning into focused, quarterly goals that align with my daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Learning Java still Worth It in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/java-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/java-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I had a dollar for every time I heard &amp;ldquo;Java is dead,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d probably be writing this from a beach somewhere. (I&amp;rsquo;m not, unfortunetly)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet, here we are in 2025, and &lt;strong&gt;Java is still one of the most widely used programming languages in the world&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, when I started diving deeper into software development, I wondered if learning Java was worth it. With so many modern languages getting all the hype, sticking with Java felt like going against the tide. But the more I explored the industry, the more I realized Java wasn’t just alive—it was thriving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial - Spring Boot &amp; AWS S3 for Image Storing</title>
      <link>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/spring-aws-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://douglas-rocha-dev.vercel.app/blog/spring-aws-s3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; my wife was busy on a Sunday afternoon. Do you know what that means? Yeah&amp;hellip; It means I&amp;rsquo;m going to code my a*s off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to start playing with AWS for sometime now, and this week I thought of an interesting use for AWS S3 at work and wanted to test it out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea is to store and retrieve images on S3 using a Spring Boot Application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
